typingclub.com 2017-02-28

# TypingClub

##### _Effective Date: May 3 rd, 2016_

TypingClub is deeply committed to protecting the privacy of our users' personal information. This privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") applies to information, including personal information, that TypingClub.com, a product of EdClub, Inc., doing business as TypingClub ("TypingClub"), collects about you when you visit our website, mobile app, or other online properties (collectively, "sites"), and it describes how TypingClub collects, uses, and shares your personal information. 

We offer several ways to use TypingClub. TypingClub offers both a limited service ("Individual Edition") and two versions of a licensed service made available through your school ("School Editions," collectively with Individual Edition, "Services"). The School Editions are available as a free, ad-supported version ("School Edition Basic") and a fee-based version without ads ("School Edition Pro"). The personal information that we collect, use, share, and disclose will depend on which of the Services you use and how you choose to use them.

**PLEASE NOTE: While most of TypingClub.com is a general audience website through which we do not knowingly collect information from children under 13 ("Children" and each, a "Child"), portions of the sites and certain Services, including, but not limited to, School Edition Basic and School Edition Pro, contain teaching and learning resources designed for students who may be Children. Students may access the sites directed to Children only after their teacher, school, or school district administrator has entered into an agreement with TypingClub. The sites that are directed to Children follow ourChildren's Privacy Policy. In addition, our use of student information is described in the "What We Collect" section, below.**

## Information We Collect

We collect information from you directly when you sign up for an account, use one of the Services, or choose to save information about your use of our Services. We also may use "cookies" and other tracking mechanisms to collect information about you when you visit our sites or Services. (A cookie is a small piece of text that a website or online service sends to a visitor's browser.) As explained in more detail below, depending on which version of our Services you use, TypingClub and third-party advertisers may send one or more cookies to your browser to help customize your experience on our sites or Services or to provide you with ads that may be of interest to you.

### What We Collect

The following are examples of the kinds of information that we may collect from you or about you:

**Basic account information.** You may establish an account with TypingClub by providing us with certain information about you, such as your name, email address, and a password. By establishing an account, you can save and track your progress on our Services. (You can use our Individual Edition without establishing an account. You cannot save and track your progress without establishing an account, however.) In addition, school officials may provide us with their email addresses which we will use to communicate with them.

**Performance information.** If you establish an account with us and choose to save your progress on our Services, we will collect information about your performance on our Services. If you use the Individual Edition and do not establish an account, we will use a cookie (described above) to collect information about your performance. This will enable us to return you to the correct webpage when you return to our sites. We will delete data we collect through the cookie within two months after you last use the Individual Edition.

**Social media account information.** You also can establish an account to use our Services by logging in through social networks and other services, such as Microsoft Single Sign-On, Facebook or Google+. If you do, we may collect certain personal information through the social network, including your full name and email address.

**Account information about school officials and student users.** After a teacher, school, or school district has entered into an agreement with Typing Club, designated school officials can register students and/or the school to use either version of the School Edition. When school officials register Students, we collect basic account information (name, email address, and password) about the students, as well as the students' grade level. We also may collect personal information about the school official, such as the school official's name, email address, password, phone number, name of school and district. (Please see our "Children's Privacy Policy," below, for information about our collection and use of information from children under 13.) 

**Other information.** Regardless of whether you establish an account with us, we may collect certain information from you when you use our Services so that we can maintain our Services and recognize you when you return to our sites. In addition, as explained in more detail below, the Individual Edition and School Edition Basic use an advertising service provided by Google that will collect information in order to target ads to you. Such information may include your IP address, the identity of your Internet Service Provider, browser type, operating system, the referring web page, and pages visited while on our sites. 

### How We Collect Information

As mentioned above, we may collect information directly from users, from students, or from school officials. In addition, we may use "cookies" and other tracking mechanisms to collect information. 

Some browsers have incorporated "Do Not Track" mechanisms. Most of these mechanisms, when turned on, send a signal to the website or online service indicating that the user does not wish to be tracked online. Our sites do not collect personal information about users' online activities over time and across third-party websites or online services. Therefore, "do not track" signals transmitted from web browsers do not apply to our sites, and we do not alter any of our data collection and use practices upon receipt of such a signal. Please note that some of TypingClub's features may not function properly when cookies are disabled or removed. For more information about Do Not Track mechanisms, see <http://allaboutdnt.com/>.

## How We Use and Share Information

We use the information described above to provide our Services to you, to communicate with you, and to manage and improve our sites and Services. Except as provided below, we will not sell, share, or disclose information we collect from or about you.

**Google Analytics.** Our sites uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google") that collects information about how visitors use the sites. Google Analytics places a cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user. Only Google can use the cookie. Google Analytics collects information only regarding the domain/IP address, or device identifier, of visitors to the sites. It does not collect names or other identifying information. We use the information Google Analytics provides to us only to improve the sites and Services. We do not combine the information that Google Analytics collects with any personally identifiable information. [The Google Analytics Terms of Use](http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) and the [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/) restrict Google's ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about visitors to the sites. You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing your return visits to the sites by disabling cookies on your browser or by installing the [Google Analytics browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). Please refer to your browser settings for additional information on disabling cookies. 

**Advertisers.** We provide advertisers with aggregated, de-identified information about the demographics and usage patterns of our users. In addition, we use Google AdSense to serve ads to users of our Individual Edition and the School Edition Basic. Google and third parties that advertise through Google may place and read cookies on your browser or use web beacons to collect information through an ad appearing on our sites. These third parties, including advertisers, may collect information, potentially including personal information, about your activities over time and across different websites when you use the Services. Any advertisements served by Google may be controlled using the [DoubleClick cookie](https://support.google.com/adsense/answer/2839090). These cookies allow Google to display ads based on your visits to this sites and other sites that use Google advertising services. However, we do not allow Google AdSense or any other service to target ads to Children using School Edition Basic. Users may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick cookie by visiting [Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/settings/ads). Deleting cookies can affect how you interact with our sites as well as other websites. In addition, deleting cookies does not mean that you are permanently opted out of all advertising programs. Unless you set your browser to block cookies, cookies can be added to your browser the next time you visit a website that uses them. Please see the privacy policy for [Google AdSense](http://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/) for additional information. You can learn more about targeted advertising by visiting <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>, which provides information regarding targeted advertising and offers an "opt-out" by participating companies in the DAA Self-Regulatory Program. You may also opt out of tracking and receiving tailored advertisements on your mobile device by some mobile advertising companies and other similar entities by downloading the App Choices app at [www.aboutads.info/appchoices](http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices). Please note that opting out through these mechanisms does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads while visiting the sites and elsewhere online.

**Service Providers.** We may use certain third parties and contractors ("Service Providers") to assist us in providing and maintaining our Services. We may allow these Service Providers access to your personal information when necessary, subject to confidentiality agreements consistent with this Privacy Policy.

**Schools and School Districts.** If you use either version of our School Edition, we may disclose personal data about you and about your performance on our sites to your school and school district. (We are not responsible for further sharing and disclosure by school officials.) We also may use aggregated, de-identified demographic and performance data to market our services to other schools and school districts.

**Additional Disclosures.** We also may disclose personal information about you with your permission, as required by law, as necessary to enforce our Terms of Service or Privacy Policy, to investigate or defend against third-party claims or allegations, to protect the security and integrity of our Services and property, and to protect our rights or personal safety and that of our users or others.

## How We Protect Your Personal Information 

We use physical, technical, and administrative safeguards to protect the personal information that we collect and that is submitted to us, both while in transit and while in storage. No method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we use reasonable security safeguards to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee absolute security.

## Children's Information

Children under the age of 13 are not permitted to use the Individual Edition. If you become aware that your Child has provided us with personal information in connection with the Individual Edition without your consent, please contact us at [support@typingclub.com](mailto:support@typingclub.com). If we become aware that a Child has provided us with personal information in connection with the Individual Edition without the parents' consent or consent of a legal guardian, we will take steps to delete such information and terminate the Child's account.

> ### **Children's Privacy Policy**
> 
> While most of TypingClub.com is a general audience website that does not knowingly collect information from children under 13 ("Children" and each, a "Child"), portions of the sites and certain Services, including, but not limited to, School Edition Basic and School Edition Pro, are directed to children under 13, and we may collect information directly from children under 13 in connection with those portions of the sites and Services. Therefore, we provide this Children's Privacy Policy to explain our privacy practices with respect to children under 13 who access and use our sites and Services.
> 
> Children may use either version of our School Edition provided that the school has complied with its obligations under the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act ("FERPA") and the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA"). If an appropriate school or school district official has consented to our collection of information from Children who are students in a manner consistent with COPPA, we will collect and use such personal information, but only for the use and benefit of the school and for no other commercial purpose. (We therefore do not allow Google AdSense or any other service to target ads to Children using School Edition Basic.) School officials may revoke at any time their consent to allow Children to use the School Editions. Furthermore, upon a parent's or a legal guardian's request, we will provide a description of the personal information we collect, give parents the opportunity to review their Child's personal information or have such information deleted and the opportunity to prevent further collection or use of their Child's personal information. Parents and legal guardians may contact us at [support@typingclub.com](mailto:support@typingclub.com).
> 
> Through this Privacy Policy, we provide each school with all the notices required under COPPA, contained within this Privacy Policy. Parents also can request a copy of these notices and request access to their child's personal information to review and/or have the information deleted by contacting [support@typingclub.com](mailto:support@typingclub.com).
> 
>   
> 
> 
> ### **Collection & Use of Information from Children Under 13**
> 
> The information we may collect on children under 13, either directly or from the school or school district, includes:
> 
>   * Required: First Name, User Name (which may be Email address)
> 
>   * Optional: Last Name, Email address, Password, Student ID, Class, Grade, School
> 
>   * Data on student activity within the sites and Services, including performance and progress within the system.
> 
> 

> 
> We do not enable children under 13 to make their personal information publicly available. We use the information collected on children under 13 to:
> 
>   * Provide reports to teachers or school or school district administrators at the class, school, or district level;
> 
>   * Support teachers or school or school district administrators implementing our products or using our services;
> 
>   * Monitor the use of our products and perform such analyses as might be necessary or helpful in improving product performance, efficiency, and security; and
> 
>   * Research how students use the sites and Services and perform analysis directed at improving the educational effectiveness of our products and services.
> 
> 

> 
> We will not use any information collected about children under 13 to directly advertise or market to students or their parents.
> 
> In addition, we may automatically collect information about the devices children under 13 use to interact with our sites and Services. The information we automatically collect may include IP address or device identifier and activity on the Services, including the date and time of use. Any usage information, device identifier, or other persistent identifier we collect is used for the sole purpose of providing support for the sites and Services' internal operations.
> 
>   
> 
> 
> ### **Disclosure of Information from Children Under 13**
> 
> TypingClub may rely on third-party service providers who provide support for the internal operations of the sites and Services, such as hosting the website, designing and/or operating our Services, tracking analytics, or performing other administrative services. These third party service providers are held to the same obligations as TypingClub with regard to information from children under 13, do not disclose or use information for any other purpose, and are subject to the terms of this agreement.
> 
> We do not provide links to external resources or chat rooms. Nor do our Services contain any offensive or inappropriate content. As a result, any school that uses the School Editions will be fully compliant with the Children's Internet Protection Act, with respect to the use of the School Editions.
> 
> For School Edition accounts, we will notify the Account Owner or Account Administrator to obtain consent prior to implementing any material changes to this Privacy Policy that increase our rights to use personal information we have previously collected about School Edition account holders.
> 
>   
> 

## Links to Third-Party Websites

As noted above, we use a third-party to deliver ads to you on the Individual Edition and on School Edition Basic. If you click on an ad, we are not responsible for any information that you provide to, or that is collected by, third parties. Such information will not be covered by this Privacy Policy, and we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of websites that you reach through advertisements on our sites.

## International Visitors

We maintain and operate our sites and Services on servers located in the United States. If you choose to use our sites or Services from regions outside the United States that have laws governing data collection and use that differ from U.S. law, you acknowledge and agree that you are transferring personal information outside of that region to the United States and, by providing such information, you consent to the use of your personal data as identified in this Privacy Policy and the transfer of your personal data to the United States.

## Business Transfers

We may sell, transfer, or otherwise share some or all of our assets, including personal information, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization, or sale of assets, or in the event of bankruptcy.

## California Privacy Rights

We do not share any personal information with third parties for the third parties' direct marketing purposes. If this practice changes, we will notify you by prominent posting on our digital properties.

The portions of the digital properties directed to students and children under 13 do not enable or have a forum for the posting or sharing of content or information.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

We ask that you read this Privacy Policy from time to time. TypingClub may modify this Privacy Policy at any time in its sole discretion. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy that increase our rights to use personal information we have previously collected about you, we will obtain your consent either through an email to your registered email address or by prominent posting on our sites. 

For School Edition accounts, we will notify the Account Owner or Account Administrator to obtain consent prior to implementing any material changes to this Privacy Policy that increase our rights to use personal information we have previously collected about School Edition account holders.

## Contact

If you have any comments or questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at 1701 Pennsylvania Avenue, NW, Suite 300, Washington, DC 20006, or [support@typingclub.com](mailto:support@typingclub.com).
